DEBBIE : It scares us just thinking about it .
When you hear it , you 're gonna think we 're insane .
ED : Try us . Please , from the start .
DEBBIE : It started out small , like a hand or a leg was in a different position .
Then its head was looking up instead of down .
And then one day , it was in a completely different room .
It was moving around by itself .
ED : Ever think maybe somebody had a key to your apartment and was playing a trick ?
DEBBIE : That 's exactly what we thought .
But never once did we find any sign or evidence of intrusion .
LORRAINE : And this all led you to believe that the doll was possessed ?
Yes .
Camilla got in touch with a medium . We learned from her that a 7-year-old girl
named Annabelle Higgins had died in this apartment .
She was lonely and took a liking to my doll .
All she wanted was to be friends .
When we heard this , we felt really sorry for her .
I mean , we 're nurses , we help people .
So
we gave her permission to move into the doll .
ED : Wait , you did what ?
She wanted to live with us by inhabiting the doll .
We said yes .
But then things got worse .
[ GIRLS LAUGHING ]
God .
CAMILLA : When we came home , she was sitting in the hallway .
But we had left her in the spare room .
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ CAMILLA GASPS ]
[ WOODEN THUNK ]
Debbie ! Debbie , wait !
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
[ BANGING CONTINUES ]
[ GASPS ]
DEBBIE : We are beyond terrified .
We don 't know what 's going on or what to do . Can you help us ?
Yes , we can .
Now , firstly , there 's no such thing as Annabelle , and there never was .
LORRAINE : Ghosts don 't possess such power .
I think what we have here is something extremely manipulative .
It 's something inhuman .
It was a big mistake acknowledging this doll .
And through that , the inhuman spirit tricked you .
You gave it permission to infest your lives .
What 's an inhuman spirit ?
It 's something that 's never walked the earth in human form .
It 's something demonic .
DEBBIE : So the doll was never possessed ?
No , no , it was used as a conduit .
It was moved around to give the impression of possession .
Demonic spirits don 't possess things , they possess people .
It wanted to get inside of you .
ED : All right , that 's good , Drew . You can shut it down now .
Hit the lights .
So we got the church to send a priest over
to bless the house and the occupants .
Whatever was oppressing that apartment was no longer with them . Any questions ?
[ PEOPLE CHATTERING ]
Yes .
Where 's the doll now ?
Someplace safe .
- Yep . - So , what are you guys ?
I mean , what do people call you ?
Uh , well , we 've been called Demonologists . That 's one name for us .
Ghost hunters , paranormal researchers .
- Kooks . ALL : Ha-ha-ha .
Wackos .
But we prefer to be known simply as Ed and Lorraine Warren .
[ CHILDREN SINGING INDISTINCTLY ]
ROGER : Here we are .
Wow , hear that ?
- I don 't hear anything . - Exactly .
Oh . Ha !
- Okay . Guys , we are here ! NANCY : Get out of the car .
Oh , God , we 're in the middle of nowhere .
CAROLYN : Are you so excited ? Where 's my " yes " ? Where 's my " yes " ? Yes !
ROGER : I 'll race you !
CAROLYN : Are you guys excited ? CHRISTINE : Yes !
CAROLYN : I 'm so excited ! APRIL : Come on , Sadie !
I get my own room !
Are you kidding me ? No dibs on the rooms !
- What ? - What ?
So do I get to pick my own room ? Or do I have no choice in that either ?
Well , first cute boy she meets , she 'll forget about Jersey .
- Great . - I hope .
ROGER : I can 't wait .
Come on , Sadie .
Sadie , let 's go .
Hey , come .
What 's the matter with you ?
Hey , come on , girl .
All right , suit yourself .
[ WHIMPERS ]
[ STATIC ON RADIO ]
[ THE ZOMBIES ' " TIME OF THE SEASON " PLAYING ON RADIO ]
- What 's your name ? - What 's your name ?
- Who 's your daddy ? - Who 's your daddy ?
- He rich ? - Is he rich like me ?
ROGER : Watch your step .
NANCY : Coming through .
Whoa , watch out , Dad .
MAN : Where do you want it ? - In the living room .
- Andrea , where 's my wind chime ? - I think Nancy 's got it in the other room .
Thanks . Hey , Nancy , have you seen my wind chime ?
- Oh , this one ? CINDY : Yeah , thanks .
- You 're gonna have to catch it . - Nancy ! Let go ! Give it here .
You 're so mean .
Hey , Mom , can I hang up my wind chime ?
Of course . There 's a line outside you can hang it on .
Honey , have April come in , okay ? It 's gonna be dark soon .
Okay .
Come on , April ! Mom wants us inside !
APRIL : Look what I found , Cindy .
[ MUSIC PLAYING FROM MUSIC BOX ]
GIRLS : One
two
three .
Come on , come on , come on . No peeking .
Four .
Are you guys done with the pizza ? I don 't want it going to waste .
- Let 's go . ROGER : It 's expensive feeding you girls .
Seven , eight , nine , ten .
Where should I hide ?
CHRISTINE : Ready or not , here I come !
Okay , clap .
[ CLAPPING ]
- Whoa ! - You don 't know the house well enough .
Someone 's gonna get hurt .
I 'm okay , I 'm okay .
Second clap .
[ CLAPPING ]
[ WHISPERS ] That 's cheating .
Clap .
- Got you ! - Aah !
- Are you okay ? Um ... NANCY : Yeah .
All right , what did we break now ?
- I didn 't mean to . - Move out of there , please .
It was Christine 's fault .
- Oh , jeez . CHRISTINE : My fault ? Oh , my God .
NANCY : Christine did it . CHRISTINE : No , I didn 't .
NANCY : You pushed me . CHRISTINE : No , no , you fell back .
Hey , Nancy , can you go get me the matches , please ?
What 's going on ?
CHRISTINE : Nancy broke something . NANCY : Shut up .
CAROLYN : What broke ? APRIL : It 's the wall .
- Whoa . - I think we have a cellar or something .
CINDY : I wanna see , I wanna see . Move , move , move .
Here , matches . Thank you .
CINDY : I wanna see . CAROLYN : You can see .
NANCY : I wanna see . CAROLYN : You can all see .
APRIL : Move !
Oh , man .
Huh .
CAROLYN : Roger ?
What do you see down there ?
Just , uh , hard to tell , you know ?
It 's an old piano and a whole bunch of garbage .
Agh . Son of a ...
Wow .
CAROLYN : Rog ?
Come on up .
I don 't want you girls going down there .
- That place is loaded with spiders . - Ew !
Just relax . Okay .
CHRISTINE : Stop it , Nancy . It 's not funny .
We 've got extra square footage anyway . I 'll check it out in the morning .
- I wonder why it was boarded up . - I don 't know .
CAROLYN : Okay , show 's over .
CINDY : Five minutes . ROGER : No more minutes .
CAROLYN : Up to bed . Please . Thank you . ROGER : Right to bed .
[ SADIE BARKING ]
ROGER : Man , I 'm fried .
CAROLYN : Something 's up with Sadie .
Yeah , I don 't know what her problem is . Couldn 't get her to come inside .
CAROLYN : We can 't leave her out there .
ROGER : She 's all right . I got her on a chain .
Sadie , hey , be quiet .
Thanks for making this work .
I know it was a lot to bite off .
It 's gonna be great , isn 't it ?
I think it 's great already .
Yeah .
You still too fried to christen the new house ?
Who said I 'm fried ?
- Ain 't nobody here 's fried . - Ha , ha .
[ FLOORBOARD CREAKING ]
CHRISTINE : Mom ?
CAROLYN : Hey . How did you guys sleep ?
I 'm cold .
It is chilly , isn 't it ?
You think maybe we could have bought a house with a toilet that actually works ?
CAROLYN : Tell your father .
And there was a funky smell in my room last night . Like something died .
- Is it still there ? - No .
Problem solved .
[ FAINT THUD ]
Roger ?
ROGER : Down here , honey .
Morning .
Ooh . Whoa .
This is gonna take some serious elbow grease .
Yeah .
Oh , my God .
[ PIANO PLAYING DISCORDANTLY ]
What are we gonna do with all this stuff ?
Well , we probably ought to go through it , you know ?
There might be some antiques down here worth a lot .
Yeah , or just a lot of junk the previous owner didn 't want .
- It 's ours now . - Knock yourself out .
- I 'm gonna make some coffee . - Okay .
I 'm gonna see if I can get this furnace working .
Yeah , that 'd be nice . It 's freezing .
Yeah .
Hmm .
APRIL : Sadie ! Come here , Sadie !
Mommy !
Mommy , where 's Sadie ?
She 's outside . You know , I 'm sure she 's hungry by now . Why don 't you go and get her .
- Whoa . - Morning , Dad .
- Can you hold this ? - Sure .
- Sadie ! ROGER : Slow it down , Scoot .
CAROLYN : Roger . - Yeah .
This clock stopped at 3 : 07 , and so did the one in the hallway .
That 's weird .
Maybe it got knocked around in the move .
Speaking of knocked around , what did you do to me last night ?
- Ouch . I didn 't do that . Did I ? - I don 't know .
Sadie !
[ APRIL SCREAMING ]
April ! April !
What 's ... ? April ! What 's going on ?
- What happened ? - Oh , my God !
Oh , Sadie .
ED : We keep everything locked in here .
Feel free to look around .
Just don 't touch anything .
Wow .
This is crazy .
So all these are taken from cases you 've investigated ?
That 's right . Everything you see in here is either haunted , cursed
or has been used in some kind of ritualistic practice .
Nothing 's a toy .
Not even the toy monkey .
Don 't touch it .
Oh , ahem . Well , isn 't it scary , or doesn 't it worry you
to have all these items right in your home ?
That 's why we have a priest that comes by once a month to bless the room .
Well , the way I see it is :
It 's safer for these things to be in here than out there .
It 's kind of like keeping guns off the street .
Why not just throw them in an incinerator ? Destroy them .
Well , that would only destroy the vessel .
Sometimes it 's better to keep the genie in the bottle .
Say , is the , uh , Annabelle doll here ?
Right this way .
Yeah .
- You said she 's a conduit ? - That 's right .
What does that mean ?
A very powerful demonic has latched itself onto her .
So when you guys investigate these hauntings
how do you stop them from latching onto you ?
We have to take great precaution .
But what about your wife ?
What about her ?
Well , Father Gordon told me that ...
Well , that was different .
What happened to my wife happened during an exorcism .
Well , what 's the difference ?
[ FLOORBOARD CREAKS ]
Excuse me .
Honey , what are you doing ?
Come here .
You know better . All right ?
Georgiana ?
- Come on . Did you touch anything ? JUDY : No .
ED : All right , come on , honey .
- Georgiana ! Could you take Judy upstairs ? - Oh , sure .
You can 't go into this room , no matter what , remember ?
- Yes , Daddy . - All right .
- Go on . - Okay , come on .
Let 's see if I can find you a little snack , okay ? Come on .
[ LAUGHING ]
Hey . What 's going on in here ?
JUDY : Daddy , look . - You look very pretty .
All right , all done . Go get dressed for dinner .
JUDY : I 'm wearing it to dinner . - No , you 're not !
Here you go .
How 'd it go ?
Oh , I think he may write a positive article .
Ooh , a non-skeptic .
That 's a pleasant change .
Yeah .
Stop blaming yourself .
No sugar .
Be right back .
[ TICKING ]
[ TICKING STOPS ]
[ GROANS ]
Not funny , Nancy .
NANCY : What ?
Stop grabbing my foot .
Shut up , I didn 't do anything .
Yeah , right .
And stop farting .
It really stinks .
Don 't blame that on me . It 's you . Pew .
[ THUDDING ]
[ THUDDING CONTINUES ]
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
[ THUDDING ]
Dad ?
Andrea , what are you doing out of bed ?
What 's that sound ?
It 's Cindy . She 's in my room . She 's sleepwalking again .
[ THUDDING ]
I 've never seen her do this before .
I remembered you saying not to wake her if she 's like this .
No , we just put her back to bed .
Hey , hey . Sweetie . Shh .
Let 's go back to bed .
She 's okay . Good night .
Night .
CAROLYN : She 's sleepwalking again ? She hasn 't done that for awhile .
She ended up in Andrea 's room too . I think kind of freaked her out .
- That 's not good . What are we gonna do ? - I don 't know .
- Honey , you got another bruise here . - Hmm ?
Does that hurt ?
That 's weird .
I don 't know . Will you do me a favor , go see a doctor for that ?
- Yeah , I will . Drive safe . - Yeah .
- I love you . - I love you too .
[ THUD ]
[ PIGEON COOING ]
Bye !
Love you !
- Cindy , you have your lunch ? - Yeah .
APRIL : Yes , I do .
I miss Sadie a lot .
She was my best friend .
You 're my friend , right ?
Yeah , let 's play .
- Who are you talking to ? - Rory .
Rory ?
- He 's my new friend . - Oh , really ?
- Yeah , do you want to see him ? - Yeah . Uh-huh . How ?
With this .
When the music stops , you see him in the mirror standing behind you .
Okay .
But you have to twist the key .
[ MUSIC BOX PLAYING ]
- Boo , Mommy ! Ha-ha ! - Oh !
- April , you just gave me a heart attack . - Got you !
Well , okay , I guess Rory doesn 't want to see me , huh ?
Hmm . Oh , well .
Can we play hide-and-clap ?
Hide-and-cla ... ? Oh , honey , I don 't want to play .
- Please ! Nobody ever lets me play . - Okay , okay .
Remember , you get to ask me for three claps .
Okay .
One , two , three .
- I 'm gonna go hide now ! - Okay .
Four , five
six , seven
eight , nine
ten !
First clap !
[ CLAPPING ]
[ CLOCK TOLLING ]
Ow . Shit .
Second clap !
[ CLAPPING ]
April .
[ HUMS ]
[ CREAKING ]
Oh , I know where you 're hiding .
Give me the third clap .
[ CLAPPING ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
I 'm gonna get you now .
[ WHEEZING ]
I can hear you breathing .
April .
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
Ha , ha . You took your blindfold off . I win !
You weren 't even warm , Mom . I was in Christine and Nancy 's room .
ROGER : I gotta have some routes here , or I 'm gonna lose the insurance on the rig .
[ CHUCKLES ]
That 's like half of my rate , man .
Yeah , okay .
I 'll , uh ... Yeah , I 'll take it .
Thank you .
- What 's the route ? - It 's , uh , Florida .
It 's a week turnaround . I start tomorrow .
We 'll get through this .
Yeah .
Come on , let 's go to bed .
Stop it , Nancy . It 's not funny anymore .
I 'm trying to sleep , please stop grabbing my feet .
[ GASPS ]
[ CREAKING ]
[ CREAKING CONTINUES ]
[ GASPING ]
[ CHRISTINE WHIMPERING ]
Nancy ?
What are you doing ?
Christine ?
Are you all right ?
Do you see it ?
See what ?
There 's someone behind the door .
What ?
There 's someone standing over there .
I don 't see anyone .
It 's looking right at us .
Nancy , don 't ! Nancy .
No , no . Look . Look .
Look , there 's no one here . See ?
Ugh . It 's that smell again .
Oh , my God .
It 's standing right behind you .
[ CHRISTINE SCREAMING ]
Christine ? ! Christine ! Christine !
God , it won 't op ...
- Christine ! - No ! No ! No !
- What 's going on ? What happened ? - There was someone else in here !
- What ? ROGER : Where ?
CHRISTINE : By the door . It was behind the door .
Honey , there 's nothing in here . There 's nobody in here .
There was someone else in here !
I was just sleeping , and then I felt somebody grab my feet .
So I thought it was Nancy .
ROGER : Well , honey , I 'm pretty sure that it was just a bad dream .
No ! It talked to me !
It said
that it wants my family dead .
[ CHRISTINE CRYING ]
LORRAINE : Mr. Winston !
JUDY : Winston ? Winston ?
LORRAINE : Get behind him .
Where you off to ?
I just gotta run to the store for a few things .
- Why do you even try ? - What ? What do you mean ?
In 15 years have you ever been able to lie to me ?
Father Gordon called . He 's got a case he wants us to look into .
I said I 'd go check it out myself . Lorraine , myself .
I 'm going with you .
I know you 're worried it 's gonna happen again .
Yeah , I am . I really am .
Maybe it 's just time we take a break . Write that book .
Do you remember what you said to me on our wedding night ?
" Can we do it again ? "
After that .
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
You said that God brought us together for a reason . Right ?
I 'm pretty sure it 's not to write a book .
I 'm gonna get dressed .
LORRAINE : We 've isolated the disturbances to the attic .
I want you to listen for a second .
[ CREAKING ]
Oh , my God , that 's it .
Do it again , Ed .
[ CREAKING ]
Right now it 's just my weight . But you take the water coming off the pipe
these boards are gonna expand and rub against each other .
You heard it all through the house because of these pipes leading to the radiator .
So this place isn 't haunted ?
No , it rarely is .
Yeah , there 's usually always some kind of rational explanation .
[ BETTE ANNE STEELE 'S " SLEEP WALK " PLAYING QUIETLY ON RADIO ]
[ GIRLS GIGGLING ]
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
[ CLAPPING ]
Girls , it 's way past your bedtime .
[ CLOCK TICKING ]
[ CRASHING ]
[ GIRLS GIGGLING ]
[ CLOCK TOLLING ]
[ CLAPPING ]
Who is that ?
[ WOOD SCRAPING ]
[ PIANO PLAYS DISCORDANTLY ]
Who 's ever down there , I 'm gonna lock you in now !
Aah ! Unh .
[ GRUNTING ]
Aah !
Help !
Andrea ! Help !
[ GIRL GIGGLES ]
[ MATCHES SHUFFLING ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
GIRL : Hey , wanna play hide-and-clap ?
Aah !
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
[ THUDDING ]
Cindy ?
Okay , now ...
All right ?
All right , come on .
Come on .
There you go .
Okay , you can just sleep with me tonight , all right ?
There .
[ BANGING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
ROGER : Andrea ? CAROLYN : Help ! Help ! Help !
- Who 's in here ? - Andrea !
Andrea ? Andrea !
In here !
Help , Daddy ! Help , it 's Andrea !
ROGER : Who 's in here ? - Andrea !
ROGER : What happened ?
[ ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY ]
Somebody , goddamn it , tell me what 's going on here ?
ED : Fear is defined as a feeling of agitation and anxiety caused by the presence
or imminence of danger .
Whether it 's a ghost , a spirit or an entity , they all feed on it .
Take Maurice here .
A French-Canadian farmer with no more than a third-grade education
yet after he was possessed , spoke some of the best Latin I 'd ever heard .
Sometimes backwards .
He 'd been molested by his father , who had also tortured him repeatedly .
A dark spirit made its home in this man .
Now , if you look into his eyes , you can see him tearing blood .
[ AUDIENCE MUTTERING ]
[ MAURICE PRIEST SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
And like that
an upside-down cross started to appear from within his body .
ED : All right , Drew , you can hit the lights .
Oh .
WOMAN : Did you personally perform the exorcism ?
No , I 'm not authorized . But I 've assisted on many .
See , an exorcism can be very dangerous
not only for the victim , but for anyone in the room .
- What happened to Maurice ? ED : He tried to kill his wife
but instead shot her in the arm and then turned the gun on himself .
Maurice had a very troubled life with little to live for
and not even an exorcist could bring him back .
Which brings us to the three stages of demonic activity :
Infestation , oppression and possession .
Now , infestation :
That 's the whispering , the footsteps , the feeling of another presence
which ultimately grows into oppression , the second stage .
Now this is where the victim , and it 's usually the one
who 's the most psychologically vulnerable
is targeted specifically by an external force .
Breaks the victim down . Crushes their will .
And , once in a weakened state , leads them to the third and final stage : possession .
- Hey , Ed ? Lorraine ? - Yeah .
There 's someone here that would like to talk to you .
- Hi . - Thanks , Drew .
- Thank you . - I 'll see you later .
How can we help you ?
There 's something horrible happening in my house . Could you come and take a look ?
You know , uh , it 's getting kinda late .
- We really need to head to our family . - You don 't understand .
But we do . There 's usually some sort of rational explanation ...
I have five daughters who are scared to death . I 'm so afraid this thing wants to hurt us .
You have a daughter . Wouldn 't you do anything you could to protect her ? Please .
Please can you come and take a look ?
Of course we will .
GIRL [ ON TV ] : Come on , Jan ! Open up !
Jan , what happened ?
[ KNOCKING ON DOOR ]
GIRL : The top of your head turned black .
CAROLYN : You guys straighten up ? Thanks .
JAN [ ON TV ] : Don 't be silly , it 's a wig .
CAROLYN : Hello . Hi . - Hi . Hi .
Thanks for coming .
- Hi , I 'm Roger . - Lorraine .
Hey , nice to meet you , Roger . Ed Warren .
- Thanks for coming . - Please , come in .
Thank you .
So ...
Oh , my God . Look at you all . Who are these beautiful young women ?
This is Andrea , the oldest , Nancy , Cindy , Christine
and April .
It 's Mr. And Mrs. Warren .
- We 're all sleeping down here now . LORRAINE : Mm .
The girls feel safer and it 's warmer .
I 'm constantly turning up the heat , but the house is always freezing .
ROGER : It 's not a problem with the furnace .
I mean , not that I can find .
CAROLYN : It 's gotten a lot worse the past few nights .
There 's this awful smell , like rotting meat . It moves around the house .
Uh ...
What ? What is it ?
Well , rancid smells could indicate some type of demonic activity .
Oh , my God .
ROGER : That 's to keep those doors from banging at night .
Otherwise , it 's like : All night long , just like that .
- Does it come in threes ? - Yeah .
It stops at dawn ?
Uh-huh .
Well , sometimes it 's meant as an insult to the Trinity :
The Father , the Son and the Holy Spirit .
ROGER : You know , it 's the damndest thing , but we also get all kinds of birds
that will just fly against the side of the house and break their necks .
Hm . Really ?
And the clocks stop at 3 : 07 a.m.
- All of them ? - Every one .
Oh , we were hanging those along the stairs .
Something just kept knocking them down , so we stopped hanging them up .
That 's what I was talking about .
It was here when we moved in .
There 's also a lot of stuff in the cellar .
Show me the cellar .
[ DISTORTED SCREAMING ]
WOMAN : Look what she made me do .
You picking up anything in here , hon ?
Something awful happened here , Ed .
Those bruises , they from something that happened here ?
Oh , it 's some iron deficiency thing I have .
You know , with all that 's been going on , why haven 't you just moved out ?
I don 't know where we 'd move to , you know ?
We got all our money tied up in this place and had a lot of repairs on top of that .
And I don 't know anybody whose gonna take in a family of seven indefinitely .
That 's why we tracked you down .
We 're glad you found us .
All right , let 's get started .
My name is Ed Warren . It 's November 1st , 1971 .
I 'm sitting here with Carolyn Perron
who , with her family , has been experiencing supernatural occurrences .
Okay , go ahead .
CAROLYN : Where do I start ?
From the first occurrence .
I guess it was the clocks .
Mom and Dad tell me that you have a friend .
His name 's Rory . He lives here too .
- Hmm . - But he 's always sad .
Why is that ?
He won 't tell me but I think something bad happened to him .
Do you mind if I try to see Rory ?
[ MUSIC BOX PLAYING ]
[ ED SIGHS ]
Hey .
[ ROPE SQUEAKING ]
What is it ?
We bought it at auction from the bank , so , you know , we never knew who lived here .
Well , Lorraine and I both feel that what your house needs is a cleansing .
An exorcism .
What , exorcism ?
I thought that was something that you do to people .
LORRAINE : No , not necessarily , no .
We have to get out of here .
I 'm afraid that 's not gonna help .
Lorraine saw something , which ...
Go ahead , hon .
I 've been seeing the dark entity that haunts your house
and your land .
I saw it first when I came through your door .
It was latched to your back .
And then I saw it again with the girls when we walked into the living room .
And it doesn 't matter where you go
this dark entity has latched itself to your family
and it 's feeding off you .
Even if we leave ?
Sometimes when you get haunted , it 's like stepping on gum .
You take it with you .
LORRAINE : Look , I gotta tell you , you have a lot of spirits in here
but this is the one that I 'm most worried about , because it is so hateful .
Okay , so what do we do ? Can we call a priest ?
ED : I wish it were that easy .
Performing an exorcism is an archaic procedure . Requires years of training .
And even then , I have seen it go horribly wrong .
But before we even get that far , the church has to authorize it first .
It means we gotta investigate , gather evidence and provide proof
and that 's the hard part .
Have your children been baptized ?
Uh , no , we never got around to that . We 're not really a churchgoing family .
Well , you may want to rethink that . Our presence here could make things worse .
Why ?
Because we 're a threat .
And whatever you 're dealing with here isn 't gonna like us .
So far it hasn 't done anything violent , and that 's a good sign .
So we 're gonna have our guy do some homework on the property
to see what we 're up against .
LORRAINE : Judy , what are you up to ?
- I got you a present . - Aah .
Me and Nanna got these at the church 's yard sale .
- Honey . - One for you and one for me .
LORRAINE : Aw . JUDY : She put a picture
of you and Daddy in mine .
Nanna said this way we 'll always be together .
You 'll be with me and I 'll be with you .
I miss you and Daddy .
Hey , hon .
Yup .
You 're not gonna believe this . Carolyn 's voice didn 't record .
What do you mean ?
Listen .
My name is Ed Warren . It 's November 1st , 1971 .
I 'm sitting here with Carolyn Perron
who , with her family , has been experiencing supernatural occurrences .
Okay , go ahead .
From the first occurrence .
Nothing .
The whole time .
- I don 't know . You find anything ? - Lots .
I mean , it 's no wonder they 're going through what they are .
That 's the original farmhouse .
It was built in 1863 by a man named Jedson Sherman
who was married to a woman named Bathsheba .
Ed , she 's related to Mary Towne Estye .
She was one of the women accused of witchcraft in Salem .
- She was hung during the trials . - Wow .
After Bathsheba married Jedson , they had a baby
and when the baby was 7 days old
Jedson caught her sacrificing it in front of the fireplace .
She ran out to that tree by the dock
climbed up , proclaimed her love to Satan
cursed anyone who tried to take her land , and hung herself .
Time of death was pronounced at 3 : 07 in the morning .
Well , that explains a few things .
Yeah , so does this .
Her last name 's Walker . She lived there in the ' 30s .
She had a boy named Rory who mysteriously disappeared in the woods .
Then she killed herself in the cellar .
And that 's not all .
So , what was the original 200-acre farm has since been subdivided and sold off .
There was another boy who drowned in a pond here . He lived in a house over here .
And a woman who worked as a maid in a neighboring home , she committed suicide too .
People who took her land .
ED [ ON RECORDING ] : I 'm sitting here with Carolyn Perron
who , with her family , has been experiencing supernatural occurrences .
Okay , go ahead .
[ LOUD WHEEZING ]
ED : From the first occurrence .
[ WHEEZING ]
[ WOMAN WAILING AND GIRLS SCREAMING ]
LORRAINE : Here 's Brad .
- You find it okay ? BRAD : Oh , yeah .
Drew , this is Officer Brad .
Officer Brad Hamilton , Harrisville , Rhode Island P.D.
Hm . Nice to meet you , man .
- So you 're the lucky new cop , huh ? - Guess so .
- You know you can 't shoot ghosts , right ? - Take it easy on him , Drew .
All right , guys , help me get this stuff unloaded .
You take this .
LORRAINE : Hi , Roger .
All right . When you 're finished here , why don 't you hit upstairs , all right , Drew ?
You got it .
ED : What 's wrong with the Chevy ?
Ugh , what 's not wrong with her ?
- Needs a new carburetor to start . - Oh , yeah ?
Kind of put fixing her up on hold for a while .
Yeah . Ahem .
Hey , Brad , hand me a thermostat , would you ?
What 's this , uh , do ?
When there 's an instant drop in temperature
the thermostat triggers the camera to take a picture .
You 've actually caught things on film ?
Well , yeah , that 's , uh , the point .
Why , uh ... ? Why out here ?
Well , this is where the witch committed suicide .
She hung herself from that branch right above where you 're standing .
CAROLYN : How could a mother kill her own child ?
It was never a child to her .
She just used her God-given gift as the ultimate offense against him .
Witches believe it elevates their status in the eyes of Satan .
[ GIRLS GIGGLING ]
Mm .
Wow . That 's a nice day at the beach , huh ?
How did you know ?
It 's an insight . It 's like a peek through the curtain into another person 's life .
Mm .
That day meant so much to me . We were driving along the coast .
Nancy pointed out how pretty the view was .
I thought this is a perfect opportunity for a photo .
We 're gonna start fresh , you know ? A new house , a new beginning .
You should have seen Roger and the girls . I 've never seen them so happy .
ALL : Cheese !
They mean the world to me .
DREW : Put your hand flat on the desk .
Yeah , and take it off .
Here we go .
See ?
It just reveals to us what the naked eye can 't see .
Pretty far out , isn 't it ?
Yeah , it 's groovy .
Drew , you got the Bolex ready for Brad ?
Yeah , already locked and loaded , sir .
[ BELL TINKLING DOOR CREAKING ]
[ TOILET FLUSHES ]
What ? I had to go .
DREW : All the rooms are coming in pretty good .
Good .
What 's in the bottle ?
Holy water .
Presence of religious icons
will get a reaction from anything unholy .
Sort of pisses them off .
So I set these throughout the house , see if I can stir things up a bit .
ROGER : Like holding a cross to a vampire ? ED : Yeah . Exactly .
Except I don 't believe in vampires .
[ BELL TINKLING ]
Wasn 't me .
[ TINKLING CONTINUES ]
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
Brad , get the camera .
Okay .
All right , it 's 9 : 18 , we 're headed down into the cellar where the door 's just opened on its own .
I have Lorraine and Officer Brad Hamilton with me .
Let 's keep the cellar light off .
Give us a sign that you wanna communicate with us .
[ LOW DRONING ]
Hon , you all right ?
There 's definitely something here .
- All right , close the door . Move something . - My hands are so cold .
Come on .
LORRAINE : No .
It 's gone . It 's gone .
ED : I got nothing .
Okay .
ED : Well , like I said , it doesn 't always work when you want it to .
Yeah , maybe the camera picked something up .
BRAD : Watch out !
DREW : For a guy who doesn 't believe
you looked a little freaked out when that door slammed shut .
It must have been a draft .
Oh , that 's funny .
A draft never put that look on my face before .
I believe the clock .
It 's 3 : 08 .
[ ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Let me see your glasses .
For you .
I think I might take some girls for ice cream later on . What do you say about that ?
GIRLS : Yeah ! ROGER : Honey , you wanna come ?
I 'm exhausted . I 'm just gonna take a nap . The late nights are getting to me .
That 's probably a good idea . Why don 't you get some rest .
- Lorraine and I 'll watch over things for a bit . - Really ?
I 'm gonna take off . I have a shift starting in an hour .
The house hasn 't felt like this in a long time .
I think the kids feel a lot safer with you around .
ED : I could get used to this . - What , me doing laundry ?
- Ha-ha-ha . - You 're funny .
No , this place .
Nice , fresh country air .
They have such a beautiful family , don 't they ?
Yeah , that little one , April , did you see her bring me pancakes ?
[ LORRAINE CHUCKLING ]
We 've gotta help them .
I know .
- I 'll start with the Chevy . - Heh .
[ ED CHUCKLING ]
[ WIND WHISTLING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ GASPING ]
Carolyn !
Are you okay ?
Carolyn , open the door .
Carolyn , open up !
[ CAROLYN COUGHING ]
Are you okay ?
- Oh , I 'm fine . - Are you sick ?
- I woke up feeling nauseous , that 's all . - I thought I saw ...
I hear Roger and the girls .
One minute .
[ GIRLS CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY ]
APRIL : Guys , do you wanna play a game ? CINDY : Boring !
APRIL : Thank you , Daddy .
NANCY : Let 's go inside .
ROGER : I thought that was you .
Hey , I hope you don 't mind .
I got a good deal on a rebuild at that wrecking yard in Smithfield .
- No , you look like you know what you 're doing . - Yeah , we 'll see .
Got a nice place here , Roger .
Lorraine and I always wanted a spot in the country .
I 'll sell you this one .
[ LAUGHING ]
Hey , hand me a wrench , would you ?
Hey , uh , it really means a lot to us to have you here .
I gotta admit , I was a little bit skeptical going in .
Just wanna say thank you , though , for coming out when you did .
I can 't take the credit . That 's , uh ... That 's all Lorraine .
- I didn 't want to . - Oh . Why 's that ?
Whatever Lorraine sees , feels , touches , it helps people .
But it also takes a toll on her .
Little piece each time .
Couple months ago we were working on a case .
She saw something .
[ PRIEST PRAYING IN LATIN ]
[ SCREAMING ]
It took a real big piece .
When we got home
she went into our room , locked herself in
didn 't talk , didn 't eat , didn 't come out for eight days .
What 'd she see ?
[ LORRAINE SCREAMING ]
Get out of here !
I don 't know .
And I won 't ask .
I need to reload . You want some ?
I 'm good , thanks .
All right .
[ WIND CHIME TINKLING ]
WOMAN [ WHISPERING ] : Look what she made me do .
[ GASPS ]
Hey .
Ed ?
Look what she made me do !
BRAD : Ed ! Ed !
Ed !
DREW : Dude , you okay ?
ED : Hold up , Brad . What 's going on ?
I saw someone . There was a woman dressed as a maid .
Ed ? Ed , we 're getting something .
ROGER : It 's just Cindy . She 's sleepwalking . - No , wait . We need this .
ROGER : Why do we need pictures of Cindy ?
She didn 't trigger it .
- What do you mean she didn 't trigger it ? - Somebody 's with her .
ROGER : Who ?
ROGER : Cindy !
Cindy !
BOY : Hey , over here . It 's safe .
There 's someone else in there with her .
I 'm hearing another voice . Here , listen .
BOY : Follow me . This way .
This is where I hide .
Cindy ?
Where 'd she go , Ed ?
Windows are locked .
Ed , where 'd she go ?
Brad , get the UV light .
- The what ? - Just ask Drew .
- Drew , I need a UV light . - Uh ...
Here , that 's it . Go , go , go , go !
Turn off the light .
Get out of the way .
Okay .
Hit the lights !
Found her .
Here we go .
- All right . You got her ? - Yeah .
That 's where Rory hides when he 's afraid .
Hon ? Could I have April 's music box , please ?
ED : How 's Cindy ? - She doesn 't remember a thing .
ED : Here you go .
Thank you .
[ SCREAMING ]
Lorraine !
No .
[ GROANING ]
Lorraine !
[ WOMAN CRYING ]
[ TINKLING FROM MUSIC BOX ]
[ MUSIC BOX PLAYING ]
[ WOMAN SOBBING ]
WOMAN : She made me do it .
She made me do it .
[ GASPS ]
[ ROPE SQUEAKING ]
[ GASPING ]
[ LORRAINE PANTING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
Ed !
Come on ! Lorraine !
[ LORRAINE SCREAMS ]
Ed !
Ed , I know what she did .
ED : I got you . I know . It 's okay . LORRAINE : I know what she did .
I know what she did . She possessed the mother to kill the child .
She visits Carolyn every night .
That 's what the bruise marks are ! She 's feeding off of her !
[ LOW RUMBLING ]
Uh ...
Nancy ?
[ ALL SCREAMING ]
ROGER : Nancy !
Are you okay ?
LORRAINE : Nancy !
ROGER : Grab her !
NANCY : Daddy ! Help !
CAROLYN : Nancy !
[ NANCY CONTINUES SCREAMING ]
CAROLYN : Is she okay ?
It 's okay , I got you .
Did you get that ?
Yeah .
I 'll have the footage developed and get it over to Father Gordon .
He 's our liaison at the church . I imagine we 'll get a pretty fast response .
- Listen , Roger ? - Yeah ?
Listen , when we get the exorcist , I 'll be back . But Lorraine ...
- Yeah , I understand . - Until then Drew 's gonna keep an eye on you .
- Hey , Ed , thank you for everything . - Yeah .
GIRL : Mommy ?
ROGER : That 's everything .
LORRAINE : Judy ?
Oh , God !
Judy ?
ED : Lorraine ! Wait !
Lorraine . What ?
Mom , it 's me . Is Judy okay ?
- What ? - Can you go check , please ?
Damn it , Mom , just check , please !
- Are you gonna tell me what 's going on ? - It 's Judy .
What ? What do you mean ?
What ?
Oh , thank God .
Mom , I 'm sorry , I didn 't mean to scare you . I 'll explain later , okay ?
What the hell happened ?
I had a vision of Judy in the water .
I know it was some kind of warning .
I know it .
Okay .
[ LORRAINE SOBBING ]
Let 's get out of here .
- So ? - Yeah , well , you weren 't kidding .
No .
Look , Ed , this is complicated because the kids aren 't baptized .
- No , I understand . - And the family are not members of the church .
- Oh , come on . - And ...
The approval would have to come directly from the Vatican .
Father , we 've never seen nothing like this .
Yeah , well , neither have I.
Father , they don 't have a lot of time .
All right .
I 'll push it through myself .
- Thank you , Father . Thank you . - Thank you .
ED : All right , we 'll wait for your call . - Yeah .
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
[ GASPS ]
JUDY : Mommy ? Daddy ?
Mommy ?
Daddy ?
[ THUNDER CRASHING ]
Dad ?
Nanna ?
[ ROPE SQUEAKING ]
[ THUNDER CRASHING ]
[ JUDY GRUNTS ]
Aah !
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
[ JUDY CRYING ]
[ BANGING STOPS ]
[ WHEEZING ]
Nanna !
Nanna , help ! Nanna , help !
Judy ?
Nanna !
Help !
- Judy ! - Nanna !
- Judy , open the door ! - Mom !
- Ed , there 's something wrong . - What ?
JUDY : Nanna !
- Judy ! - Help !
- Judy ! Judy , open this door ! ED : What is it ?
LORRAINE : What 's wrong with her ? Judy ! ED : Hey , move . Move , move , move , move .
Judy , get back , honey . Get back !
ED : Come on ! LORRAINE : Hurry .
Help ! Help !
ED : Get away from the door , Judy !
Aah !
Oh , God ! Are you okay ?
There was someone rocking in the chair with Annabelle .
[ JUDY SOBBING ]
LORRAINE : What ?
It 's okay .
She 's still in the case .
It 's okay . It 's okay .
- Dad ! Dad ! - Daddy !
Dad ! Dad ! Mom just left with Christine and April .
She went in the car and drove away . I don 't know what happened .
- She smells like rotting meat . - She didn 't say what was going on .
- What do you mean , she left ? Left where ? - Gone ! I don 't know where she was going .
Where are we going , Mom ?
[ PHONE RINGING ]
- Hello ? ROGER : It 's Roger .
Something 's going on with Carolyn .
Andrea was here , said Carolyn took off with Christine and April .
- The girls said she smelled like rotten meat . - She possesses the mother
to kill the child , that 's what she does . She 's taking them to the house .
Roger , get back to the house now . I 'll meet you .
Lock the door , close the blinds . Stay off the phone !
Go .
LORRAINE : I 'm coming . - No , you stay with Judy .
The only way to protect Judy is if we stop this where it started .
- Otherwise , she 'll latch onto us again . - That 's exactly why I am going .
You think I 'm gonna let you walk into this alone ?
I can 't lose you .
You won 't .
Let 's finish this together .
[ SIREN WAILING ]
ED : Agh ! It 's locked . LORRAINE : Carolyn !
ED : Roger !
BRAD : Get out of the way !
[ CAROLYN SCREAMING ]
ED : Roger ! ROGER : Ed !
ED : Carolyn ! ROGER : Ed !
- Carolyn ! ROGER : We 're down here !
Carolyn , don 't ! No , no ! She 's got ... !
Get her hand ! Get the scissors !
[ CAROLYN CONTINUES SCREAMING ]
ED : We gotta get her to the car ! BRAD : And bring her where ?
To take her to the priest for the exorcism .
ROGER : Where 's April ? DREW : April ?
April !
Take Christine to the car and find April !
DREW : April !
Come on !
[ CAROLYN SCREAMING ]
[ CONTINUES SCREAMING ]
- She won 't let her leave the house . - What do you mean ?
- If we take her out , the witch will kill her . - Agh !
[ CAROLYN SCREAMING ]
Roger !
Carolyn !
ED : Go !
Carolyn ?
[ CAROLYN SCREAMING ]
Okay , I 'm gonna put you in here . Come on .
- Get in . Stay in here . - I don 't wanna stay here by myself .
Stay in here no matter what . I 'll be back .
I have to find April , okay ? I 'll be back , I promise .
April ?
You okay ?
[ ALL GRUNTING ]
Stop !
Brad ! Brad !
Aah !
Let 's get something to tie her up !
LORRAINE : Hold it .
[ CAROLYN SCREAMING ]
I gotta call Father Gordon . We gotta get him out here .
He 's too far away . She won 't make it . Look at her .
- Then you need to leave . - What are you talking about ?
I have to do it . The exorcism .
What ? I thought you said we need a priest . You 're not a priest .
- Well , you got a better idea ? - He can do it .
- You can do it . - But you gotta get out of here .
- I 'm not leaving you ! - Damn it , I 'm not doing this with you in here !
God brought us together for a reason . This is it .
I 'm gonna get the book .
[ CAROLYN SCREAMING ]
DREW : April !
April !
[ CAROLYN GROANING ]
" In the name of the Father , the Son , the Holy Spirit . "
[ SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ RUMBLING ]
[ CHRISTINE GASPS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
April !
[ THUDDING ]
[ CROW SQUAWKS ]
[ BANGING THEN DREW GASPS ]
[ CROWS SQUAWKING ]
[ RUMBLING ]
[ SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
[ IN ENGLISH ] Hold her still ! Hold her still !
Come here ! Hold her still !
[ SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
April ?
[ APRIL WHIMPERING ]
April !
April , you under there ?
[ ED SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
Carolyn . Carolyn . Don 't give in ! Don 't let her take you !
Ed ! You gotta stop , you 're killing her . Stop !
No , he can 't !
CAROLYN : Roger , help me !
[ ED CONTINUES SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
Ed ! Goddamn it , stop it !
Understand this ! We are now fighting for her soul !
" In the name of Jesus Christ , the saints and all the angels
I command you to reveal yourself ! "
[ SCREAMING ]
[ CLANGING ]
CAROLYN : Roger , help me !
[ ED SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
[ ED CONTINUES SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
[ SCREAMING ]
ED [ IN ENGLISH ] : Put her down !
Put her down !
ROGER : Carolyn !
Carolyn !
LORRAINE : Ed , look out ! - Unh !
LORRAINE : Are you okay ?
[ CAROLYN LAUGHING ]
ED : Hold her still ! Don 't let her up !
We 're losing her , Roger !
Damn you ! You leave my family alone , you hear me ?
I don 't know what you are , but you leave my wife alone , goddamn it !
Let her go ! Do you hear me ? Let her go !
[ SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
Let her go , goddamn it ! Let her go !
[ ED CONTINUES SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
She 's already gone .
And now you 're all gonna die .
[ GUN COCKS ]
April !
I found her ! She 's under the house ! Under the kitchen !
Don 't ! No !
Get her !
[ ALL GRUNTING ]
ED : Here . ROGER : Carolyn !
[ APRIL SCREAMING ]
ROGER : Carolyn ! DREW : She 's in that hole . Right there .
Carolyn ? Oh , my God . No !
Can 't go in . Can 't reach .
ROGER : No ! Carolyn , don 't !
[ APRIL SCREAMING ]
Carolyn , no !
Bathsheba !
By the power of God , I condemn you back to hell !
[ SCREAMING ]
This is your daughter !
[ WAILING ]
- You can 't give in ! - Agh !
Roger . We need to get her to fight from the inside .
Don 't let her do this . Don 't let this thing do this .
You gotta fight it . You 're stronger than she is .
- You gotta fight ! - Keep it going , Roger !
You gotta stay with us , all right ? Come on back , Carolyn .
You 're in , that 's it ! Get her back !
- Remember what you showed me . - No !
Remember that day that you said you would never forget .
[ ALL LAUGHING ]
[ SOBBING ]
LORRAINE : You said they meant the world to you .
This is what you 'll be leaving behind .
[ SOBBING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ COUGHING ]
[ RETCHING ]
APRIL : Mommy ?
[ WHIMPERING ]
Oh .
ROGER : It 's over .
I am so sorry .
I love you so much . I love you so much .
I love you so much .
I 'm so happy .
A draft do that to your face ?
I 'd take a guy with a gun any day .
You did good .
No , you did .
I 'll call Father Gordon and let him know what happened .
Sounds good .
The Vatican approved the exorcism .
Heh . Nice timing .
And if we can , then he 'd like to meet with us tomorrow .
There 's a case in Long Island he 'd like to discuss .
Really ?
[ MUSIC BOX PLAYING ]
[ English - US - SDH ]
[ THUNDER CRASHING ]
[ BANGING ON DOOR ]
[ JUDY CRYING ]
[ BANGING STOPS ]
[ CHAIR SQUEAKING ]
Nanna !
SAFRAN : You know , being scared is like being made to laugh .
It 's an instinctive reaction .
When something scary is happening , you just feel it automatically .
MAN : A mark .
SAFRAN : Getting James on board this project was a home run for us .
When the screenplay was ready to go out to directors
and we were putting together our list
there was one name that was the top of everybody 's list .
New Line 's , Warner Bros. , mine . And that was James ' .
He was the only director that we ever went to on this movie .
I wanted to do something I haven 't done before
and that is basically deal into the world of , you know
telling a biographic story .
So , what are you guys ?
Ghost hunters , paranormal researchers .
- Kooks . ALL : Ha-ha-ha .
But we prefer to be known simply as Ed and Lorraine Warren .
The crucial aspect for me was the real-life inspiration
of Ed and Lorraine Warren .
WAN : I could pull from a lot of the stories they 've had in the past
I think they investigated over 10,000 cases in their lifetime .
And so that means , you know , a lot of great materials to pull from .
James is able to
elevate the level of the genre
to a point where you don 't necessarily need the blood
you don 't need the guts to scare people .
[ CRASHING ]
[ GIRLS GIGGLING ]
That 's actually drawing him to the room and talking to her .
His artistry is off the charts .
You know , his visual sense , his production design sense
his eye for the camera , he gets the rhythm .
It 's less about cheap scares , it 's about where do you put the camera
how do you frame it , how do you use empty spaces to build suspense with ?
I want it to feel very real . I always , when I create these scenes
I want to put you , the audience , in there with the family
so one of the tricks I do a lot of is if a character 's walking down a hallway
I would always have the camera be behind the character following down the hallway .
So you 're there with them . You 're walking with them .
And so you don 't know what 's in front of them .
Yeah , maybe the camera picked something up .
Watch out !
WAN : Cool .
And you can see it in the actors that they respond to that .
That they understand what he 's trying to get .
Not only just performance-wise , but also by moving the camera in certain ways
to build up the suspense and build up the scares .
Sometimes in these kind of movies you write too many scares .
Because you think it 's gotta be scare after scare .
You can 't do that , you gottajust build , slow it down .
Actually , that 's one thing that James said , his first read , he goes :
- " I love all these scares , there 's too many . " - " We gotta pull some of these out . "
We 're like , " This is a horror movie , James . " And he goes :
" We have to build the tension . We 're gonna build more tension
between the scares . " He goes , " Trust me . "
Yeah , he was spot-on .
My approach for the scares and the suspense sequences in this film
are definitely much ... Are based much ... Are much more grounded .
I tried to put into the film , you know , things that happened to the family .
You know , things that they would see , that they would experience in this house .
You know , a rocking chair on its own .
Like a creaking door .
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
Those are classic haunted house horror movie tropes .
But there 's a reason why they 're there because when they work , they 're so effective .
Nanna ?
[ WHEEZING ]
I 've always said what makes scary movies work
is not so much the visual
it 's the sound , it 's what you think you see
through the sound design that is the most important thing .
Keep coming around , come around , and then he starts to back away here , and the thud
as we go along .
[ THUD ]
[ GASPS ]
[ PIGEON COOING ]
There 's a difference in wanting to scare an audience
and wanting to trick an audience .
James is one of those people that would never want to trick an audience .
It 's not about fooling them into thinking this is something different .
He loves to scare you , but he 's just not gonna trick you .
[ SNARLS ]
[ WOMAN SCREAMING ]
And to me , why I think
the haunted house subgenre or the haunting genre is so enduring
is it takes place in a world that we all understand
which is it takes place in the home .
What has been fantastic for me on this film
for me to realize my vision , we literally built this two-story house inside a stage .
And that was amazing , you know , just , like , seeing how quickly it came together .
And how , you know , we would talk about ...
And how Julie would find ways to accommodate what I ...
How I wanna shoot my sequences .
The driving force is I need to achieve what the script had .
And what James wants , his vision .
COWAN : We realized very much what we 've been saying about how James frames a shot
and what he needs out of each scene
is that doorways had to be in an exact spot to make the scare work .
And hallways needed to be a certain length and a certain darkness
to be able to kind of have things come out of them and make them scary .
TAYLOR : The details were so fantastic , you know ?
Um , so I just love when a production designer is on that level , I just ...
I just love when they 've just filled in every little ... They filled the canvas in .
For me , I take all these stories and I try to filter it through myself .
I try to think of it through my own head , going , " Okay , what scares me ? "
Roger !
When I first read the script , the more I started designing that end sequence , I realized :
" Wow , that could be a really cool , iconic moment for the film . "
I kind of didn 't wanna show her face when she was transforming
into , like , this scary person .
And so the way to do that was
we had Lily 's character
attacking someone , attacking Brad , the cop character
and biting him in the face .
[ SCREAMS ]
And in doing so , that allowed me to muzzle her
with a sheet across her and basically spent the rest of the exorcism
with her underneath this white sheet
you know , wrapped around this white sheet tied to a chair .
[ GRUNTING ]
And then , you know , for that moment where she starts coughing and hacking up blood .
[ COUGHING ]
You know , she coughs up the blood , but because the sheets are in her face
the blood sprays onto the inside of the sheet and so it adds this extra
really sort of gritty layer to it , to what 's going on .
And I think it just makes it really creepy .
[ ED SPEAKING IN LATIN ]
The key is to , you know , make a scary film
that has a lasting impact and that affects people way after the film is over .